Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) Project Newsletter UP177
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) Project Newsletter
1984 -- 1986
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
UP177
0.5 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the monthly/bimonthly newsletters that outlines the progress and problems of the Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) project.
Biographical / Historical
The Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) Project Newsletter began circulation in October 1984 for the purpose of outlining the development and problems of the NILP Project and providing a space for debate on its progress. Welcoming contributions from interested parties, the NILP Project Newsletter provided information about the status and future goals of the Project, responses to drought and other challenges, and updates on relevant travel of Tufts personnel. Issues also provide some related context about Niger and pastoral agriculture. The NILP Project Newsletter was edited by Gillian Garb and received through a mailing list primarily from the North Grafton campus of Tufts University. Due to the reduced scope of the project, the final issue of the newsletter was circulated in November of 1986.
The Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) project was established in November of 1983 with the signing of a $17.5 million grant agreement between the Government of Niger and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID). This project succeeded the Niger Range and Livestock (NRL) project, which began in 1977 and involved the investment of $5 million by USAID to research the sahel region of Niger in order to understand current practices and assess the needs of the population affected by low-herd productivity, malnutrition, illiteracy, and periodic droughts. This research was then used to inform the work of NILP and determine appropriate assistance.
On December 29, 1982, Tufts University signed a contract with USAID for $399,000 to design a livestock production project in Niger. As part of the agreement between the government of Niger and USAID in 1983, Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine, Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, and the School of Medicine joined other institutions in signing a $19.5 million contract that would provide these institutions with $12.4 million to design a livestock management system intended to increase livestock production and thus improve the health, nutrition, and literacy of 18,000 herders. After food donations proved to be inadequate to solving issues of hunger, poverty, and low-production, the NILP contract sought to provide a sustainable institutional and policy framework that would improve the herders' ability to self-sustain, optimize land use, and improve the efficiency of production.
From the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine (TUSVM), associate professor of preventive medicine and epidemiology Dr. Albert Sollod worked as a consultant for USAID, traveling to Niger during the period of NRL before NILP. After the commencement of NILP, Dr. Sollod worked alongside Dr. J. Dirck Stryker, associate professor of international economic relations at the Fletcher School, and Dr. Morton A. Madoff, professor and chairman of the Department of Community Health at the School of Medicine at Tufts University, to provide an interdisciplinary approach to the project and train herders in veterinary medicine as well as range management and livestock economics.
- Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) Project Newsletter, 1984 -- 1986; UP177.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the monthly/bimonthly newsletters that outlines the progress and problems of the Niger Integrated Livestock Production (NILP) project.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1984-10; UP177.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Volume, issue
    1, 1
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1984-12; UP177.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
    1, 2
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-01; UP177.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
    1, 3
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-02; UP177.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    1, 4
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-03; UP177.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    1, 5
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-04; UP177.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
    1, 6
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-05; UP177.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
    1, 7
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-06; UP177.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
    1, 8
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-07 -- 1985-08; UP177.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    1, 9
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-09; UP177.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
    1, 10
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1985-10; UP177.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    1, 11
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1986-01; UP177.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
    2, 1
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1986-02 -- 1986-03; UP177.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
    2, 2
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1986-04; UP177.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
    2, 3
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1986-05 -- 1986-06; UP177.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
    2, 4
  - Niger Intergrated Livestock Production Project Newsletter, 1986-11; UP177.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
    2, 5